Great. Automotive service is
[Music]
Morning
everybody. And I say good morning
because I had time and I fell asleep uh
at home before I came. So, excuse me if
I'm a little groggy. Apparently, I
couldn't spell on the
agenda either. Sorry, Mr. Bisjack. Uh
welcome to the finance committee meeting
for October 6th. Uh we have just a
handful of resolutions and ordinances
and a light crowd this evening. So we'll
get started with temporary resolution
coming through finance that is the 2026
budget. So first edition I will kick it
over to the mayor if you want to
>> certainly
>> start us off. So I want to give you some
the high level information on the
starting of the budget process.
Obviously this is the first reading and
the budget is essentially what was
submitted by department heads on what
they need, what they want, what they
wish for. Uh we've able to meet with all
department heads up to this point and uh
we are currently coming through the
budget and there'll be there'll be
significant significant changes as we go
through the process. But let me give you
some information help you understand
where we're at.
Um, unions police fire complex have
negotiated a 5% raise for the upcoming
year. That's part of the collective
bargaining agreement. And this is the
final year. We're going into the final
year of a three-year contract.
Uh, ASME negotiated a 4% raise and then
in the final final year of their
three-year contract in 26.
Um, another important note is we have 27
pays in 2026.
It impacts the city in the following
way. Overall, $1.8 million for payroll
and a general fund, $1.234 million for
that payroll. So, when you see those
numbers and you look at, you'll see that
increase budgeted for 2026.
U management and non-UN pay rate uh
raise is set at 2.5 for 2026.
uh health insurance increase uh
is 3%. And that is well below the area
standard. Uh we want to keep as low as
possible when we can, but we we did see
we need to make a small change to offset
cost.
Uh note enterprise, we talked about this
when legislation comes forward.
Enterprise funds and departments are
seeing uh increased project cost and
material cost. you'll see that budgeted
in their line items to account for that
going forward.
Um
we also have uh met with the departments
as and as we did uh we discussed
vehicles. Vehicles are always a big
cost. Some of them are extremely
expensive like a fire engine and some of
them are more reasonable like a a truck
for uh code enforcement. However, we set
some general guidelines on how old a
vehicle should be, what type of
condition should be in before we seek
replacement, and we've also uh set a a
standard price for the type of vehicle
that really hasn't been uh outlined
before.
So, you're getting first reading
when you go through it. If you have
questions, contact you department head
directly if you'd like to, but certainly
me or uh the service safety director and
we'll have answers for you. We'll find
them for you. Uh I would ask that as we
go through the budget, you're going to
see changes in in amendments. So, we'll
probably amend it.
We hope to have one amendment, but it's
likely we'll have more than one
amendment. Um we'll find things that we
need to change as we go through the
process.
The idea of bringing it forward now is
to give everybody enough time to read
it, get answers when they need them. Um,
try to understand things that maybe
you're not fully aware of by getting
with the appropriate person, department
head or whoever the expert might be in
that area. And then we can all come to a
conclusion and pass a budget in time for
uh 2026.
So, I realize that's a high level view
of where we're starting. Any any
questions I can answer?
Anyone?
Awesome. Yeah, I appreciate um SSD Woody
sent out a you should have all got an
email with a digital copy of that on
Saturday so we can start combing through
it. So
if there are any other questions, we'll
leave it at that and move on. Uh
temporary resolution 8425 is coming
through safety committee. Mr. Bisjack.
>> Uh thank you, Mr. chair. Uh this is
going to be a reappropriation of $75,000
from uh the salary administration fire
line item to the overtime fire
department line item. Uh the reason for
this change here for this
reappropriation I should say and I want
to emphasize this is money that's
already been budgeted for and this is
not coming from the unencumbered
balance. Uh but the reason for this
change is since uh the fire department
has not hit hit maximum staffing for the
2025 year. Uh there was some money left
over in the salary. uh and combined with
the fact that we've had, you know,
injured firefighters, pregnancies, child
births, things like that, folks on light
duty, um over time has, you know,
surprisingly crept up. So, this uh line
item change here, reappropriation is to
accommodate that. And I have been
assured here by the fire chief that this
is a worst case scenario here. So, this
should carry us through for the rest of
2025. That's all I have, Mr. President,
or Mr. Chair, excuse me.
>> Any questions?
>> No. Pretty straightforward. Yeah.
>> And a council member will be my uh Tina
will be my second. Excuse me. And we'll
be going three readings on this one.
Okay.
>> Oh, I do have one thing.
>> Yes.
>> I just wanted Well, three readings. I
mean, do they people need paid before
that? There's three readings. I mean, is
that too far to go? Are people
>> just making sure.
>> I appreciate the question. So, we are
looking at the forecasting like kind of
the worst case scenario. Okay. Um it
appears that we'll have sufficient
funding in the overtime line um to get
us through to the third reading of this.
Um if something changes, I would come
back and okay ask council to entertain
um speeding that timeline up. Um you
know, we are coming closer to the end of
the year. We do expect to be at full
staffing um here very soon. We have two
firefighters who are going through that
process to get started with us. Um but
we also have a lot of special duty
happening right now with the Fairfield
County Fair and events like that. So,
we're monitoring it very closely and if
there's going to be any changes, we'll
definitely let council know. Thank you.
>> Did you kind of come up short because of
what happened at the fair? You had all
that overtime and that did that kind of
play into that?
>> Well, as as Councilman Bisjack pointed
out, from the beginning of the year,
we've had nine people at different times
on light duty that we just didn't
anticipate um when we're budgeting for
overtime. Um, also as I mentioned the
special duty that comes out of our
regular overtime funds um, not just for
the fair but for all the other events
that we have approved and we do
throughout the year. Um, for that we're
reimbursed
but the reimbursement money doesn't go
back into that overtime account. It just
goes back into the revenue for
carryover. Um, and it's not immediately
available to go back into that account.
>> Okay.
>> I just want to make sure that people
aren't getting they you didn't need it
ahead of time.
>> I appreciate that. No, I think we're
okay for now. Thank you. Any
other questions?
Awesome. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> All right. Temporary resolution 8525
coming through administrative services.
Mr. Luenberg.
>> Yes. Uh thank you, chairman. Um I'd like
to ask the service safety director to
speak to this one if you would.
>> Absolutely.
>> Thank you.
>> Not that I want to. Um so as you all
know, we are self-insured. So that means
that although United Healthc Care is our
insurance carrier, the city of Lancaster
pays all of its claims directly to
United Healthcare.
Unfortunately, we had a medical claim
that came through last month that was a
$1.4 million claim at Children's
Hospital. That's one claim. That's kind
of unheard of. You don't typically get a
$1.4 million claim in one year. Um but
because of that one significant claim,
it means that we have exhausted a lot of
our expense budget for our claims. Now,
with us being self-insured, we do have
stop-loss insurance. So, anything over
$150,000,
we will end up getting some
reimbursement back.
So, anything over the $150,000, we will
get some reimbursement back for that.
However, in the meantime, we still need
to make certain that we have enough
money in our expense budget to continue
to pay any additional claims that we
would receive through the end of the
year. So, because of the one significant
claim, I'm asking to appropriate from
our unencumbered
fund, 1.8 million, to make certain that
it covers that $1.4 million claim and
any additional extra claims that we just
haven't anticipated through the end of
the year. And with that, I will ask for
any questions.
This won't affect anybody else's budget
or any other
>> correct. Okay.
>> We have a carryover in our medical
claims.
>> Good.
>> That we have it in there. It's not
coming out of general fund. It's coming
out of the health insurance money. Um
we're just asking to appropriate it out
of that unencumbered into the expense
budget.
>> Excellent.
>> Thank you.
>> And we have no choice. I mean it's
there. So there we have no choice at
this. It doesn't matter. I mean, that's
just that's how unfortunately how
healthc care is and so Lancaster has no
choice but we have to fulfill it.
>> Thank you,
>> Mr. Chairman. Can I add a couple things?
>> Yes, sir.
>> I had elected official call me and asked
me if I would explain a little bit about
how we're funded uh for self-insured
uh safety director explain most of it,
but I just want to add a couple things.
So, the reason we have carryover and
we're able to move that money from the
unencumbered balance to and cover this
cost is because we share uh with our
employees
each month that the city pays part of
the premium,
we'll call it a premium, part of the
health insurance coverage and the
employee pays part of that. That's
typically negotiated in collective
bargaining, but currently it's 15. They
pay 15%, the city pays 85%.
That builds over time. We were able to
build it up and and now we have a
balance to cover something like this.
Um,
but it is self-insured. That's why we
have stop loss. That stop-loss kicks in
at 150,000 above, but it is reimbursed
and not paid in advance. So, they don't
just take it off our shoulders. We have
to pay it and then we seek a return of
that that money. Also, um,
like insurance, we use a administrator
to administer our our health insurance
coverage. So, for the employee, it seems
like health insurance, but really for
us, it's it's paid for by the city and
by the employee over time. Uh, again, I
had somebody call me and ask me if I
would explain that. Hopefully, I've
explained it fairly fairly well, but it
really is not traditional health
insurance. It's a self-insured program.
>> So, will stop lock repay everything over
150,000?
>> It will.
>> Wow, that's super.
>> But it'll probably raise our stop loss
coverage for next year.
>> Yeah, I was going to ask about premium.
>> Yeah,
>> probably.
>> You can have an accident.
>> Anything else? Any other questions?
>> No, we'll go three readings and uh Mr.
Bezek will be my second.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Uh temporary resolution 8625 coming
through finance committee is the county
budget commission levy rates. So I'll
kick that over to auditor nettles. Um
this is an annual piece where as you can
see with the attachment um exhibit A,
it's the schedule A that the county I
received from the county auditor's
office which is giving the estimated
real estate tax rates for collections in
2026 on 2025 tax year. So they're kind
of giving those values. They're not
something that is negotiated. It's
something that they give out to every
entity and they're requesting um this
resolution for council to adopt those
rates and it got missed in translation
um because we hadn't done this in the
past two years because they amended the
the county's budget commission kind of
amended how the tax budget um was done.
Um, previously the tax budget would come
before city council, but um between the
county auditor auditor and the um county
budget commission, they um loosen the
reigns on that. So now council doesn't
have to approve it and it it's still
done, but it's done on the back end and
I converse back and forth with the
budget commission as needed for that. Um
but they now decided that they still
need this per an OC that was due by the
end of September. So, we're kind of in a
catchup mode. So, if um I can have one
reading on this, I'd be eternally
grateful.
>> Any questions?
>> No, I will request suspension when we
get to the
>> Yeah.
>> One other thing. Did we put the one
where the first whereas that it was
removed for?
>> Yes, we removed it and it was delivered
to a nitro earlier.
>> Okay.
>> Y question. I mean, this is this hasn't
we haven't seen this for the last couple
of years.
>> For two years. Yes. They didn't send it
to me for the past two years. And this
is the last time it was before city
council, which was in 2022. Um that was
when they made their changes. In 23 and
24, they did not send me this
resolution. This resolution comes from
the county auditor's office. Um this
>> Well, I just have a question. Does this
represent any kind of a tax increase on
anyone? This is the real estate taxes
that you paid and and the estimated
city's portion that we will receive from
the tax collector.
>> Okay. Okay. So,
>> they do those calculations at the county
auditor's office. They send them out to
the schools. They send them out to what
they believe on real estate taxes will
come to us through the normal
collections. And of course then you see
the um road improvement which is the 3M
levy what they believe is the gross
collections that they should collect and
send us in 2026.
>> I just want to make sure we were not
approving or voting on any kind of a tax
agreeing to
>> we're just agreeing to the monies that
we anticipate are going to come our way.
>> There's not a bartering system. We can't
change those rates. The rates are what
they are.
>> Okay. Great. Thank you.
Any other questions?
Okay, I will be asking for suspension
this evening. Mr. Als would be my second
uh ordinances. Moving on to ordinance
temporary ordinance 5425 coming through
service committee. Mr. Hails.
>> Uh yes, Hank To from the gas department
is here to discuss this.
Good evening. What we're looking for is
um a smart meters AMR automated
um
to replace our
old meters. Um mainly what we want to
start out is um do a pilot program in uh
certain areas, remote places are hard to
read. Um, the biggest thing that we need
city council approval for is for the FCC
licensings that is part of this to
remotely read the meters.
Any questions?
So, this has nothing to do that they've
already purchased some meters. That's
within their right to do that. This is
just the FCC license.
>> Yes. Thank you.
And Mr. Wing is my second.
>> Three readings, please.
>> Two readings. Any questions? We have the
nice Q&A. So any between now and the
next meeting. All right. Uh thank you.
Temporary ordinance 5525 coming through
finances is the council pay ordinance.
Um,
>> anyone want to discuss that?
>> Do you want me to take it?
>> Or you want to take it?
>> Sure, I'll take it. Um, we have to set
the um, pay for council with every term.
We've chosen to leave it the same as it
was last term and it's just a formality
that it takes place.
It's laid out in front. Anyone have any
questions?
No.
be three readings. Mr. Sullie will be my
second on that one.
And then finally, we have temporary
ordinance 5625 coming through economic
development. Mrs. Hoop,
>> thank you. Um, this is just the Sheridan
Drive TIFF. This is the commercial side,
so it's the multifamily
um apartments. I think there's about
250ish
of them.
And this is to accept
or to not to accept but to begin.
And Mrs. K was supposed to be my or will
be my second and it's going to go three
readings.
>> Um there you are. Hi.
>> I'm here to answer any questions. Before
I ask my anyone have any questions for
Miss Pasco?
>> Do you want do you want to explain in
depth anymore?
>> Um, so the way the tiffs work is they
separate uh multi-tenant from single
family homes. It's it does not make
sense in my head, but they call
multi-tenant commercial and single
family homes residential. So, this is
just the um single family portion of it
and we're going to have a public hearing
November 3rd. Um and then
um later down the road, we will do the
commercial side. The commercial side's
really short. The residential side, it
has a lot more pieces and parts to it, a
lot more um holding periods where we
hold for 30 days. So, um, so yeah, and
this is for Sheridan.
>> Any questions?
I guess my question is, and and maybe
it's I'm going to include another one,
but like they know the developers know
that these are available, right? I feel
like we we these have keep getting added
on at the very last minute, like it was
an afterthought and they're like, "Oh,
can we do this, too?" because they're
seeing someone else do it.
>> So, we've been talking to this developer
for a while. Um, they have all asked us
for tiffs. We do not suggest they get a
tiff. Um, but the um the the thing is is
that the process takes a bit of time and
we need to get it in before the end of
the year. So, that's why it feels very
rushed. It feels like we're throwing it
out. While we've been talking about it
with the developer, we haven't uh I
haven't done a good enough job of
letting you know what's coming down the
the pike, but we have to get it done
before the end of the year to utilize
the tiff to its uh biggest advantage,
best advantage.
>> I I think it because it was it in your
update email where now
>> there will be one more. Yes. Now, Casto
is asking for it on the property or the
Taylor property.
>> Yes. Now, um
>> so I felt like that was like, oh,
>> can we do that, too?
>> I promise that we have asked them for
about a year and a half if they want to
do this tiff. We thought, you know, uh
we work with Bricker Graden and we we
said, Bricker, they're not doing it.
We've asked them a million times and
they they have uh yet to uh approve it
and time is running out. Um but they
came at us maybe a week or two ago. I
mean it was we were all like, "Oh, we've
asked you a thousand times if you wanted
to do this." So the good news is is
that's a commercial tiff. Um it is
commercial development. It's going to be
quick. And as always, we make these
nonschool. So the schools are made
whole. Um so that yes, that will be
coming down the road. Um but I let you
guys know as soon as pretty much as soon
as we knew it was within a week that we
kind of got it all together and looked
at a timeline. So and again they want to
get it done before the end of the year.
And we had told them that it would take
quite a bit longer. So that's why we
thought we were out of that window and
we said they're obviously not going to
do it. They're not responding to us. So
I guess in the process when is it like
sorry you forgot to ask and you missed
the boat on that. So I actually when I
when I received the email that said that
they are in they are interested in doing
it that that they will proceed with the
tiff. I thought oh they ran out of time
but the commercial tiff is just so
compressed that there is more than
enough time in terms of city council
meetings going three readings um and
doing kind of the due diligence that the
process due diligence that we do on our
side.
>> Okay.
Any other questions?
No. Okay. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> So, Miss Hoop, I have down here three
readings and Mr. Crates will be your
second again.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Okay. All right. Any more
resolutions, ordinances to come tonight?
No. Uh, I am open for department
updates. Anybody?
Sparse crowd. Anybody with department
updates?
Yes, ma'am.
>> I'll just give a quick update in that
you got your first reading of the budget
this evening. Typically, we have pay
ordinances that accompany the budget and
we will most likely have those to
introduce at our next council meeting.
So, just to give you a heads up, that
will be coming.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Seeing no one else, turn over to
President Porter for tonight's meeting
prep.
Uh thank you, Chairman Skunover. Tonight
we have a special presentation from the
Small Business Administration. Um and I
think it's in relation to the flooding
which occurred earlier this year. So
that is um the only thing out of the
ordinary on the agenda this evening.
>> Great. Thank you. Uh any other items for
finance?
Ma'am,
>> I just wanted to come tonight because I
had the piece of legislation that you
had the first reading on at your last
meeting. I apologize for the fact that I
couldn't be here, but I was at um our
fall conference up in Cleveland that
evening it started. Um, so I just wanted
to come to councel because when I had
initially asked for the um the
legislation that put that added funds to
my postage account, I had I thought that
three readings would be sufficient. I'm
respectfully asking if we could cut that
down to two readings. And the reason is
and I have some paperwork. I had
forwarded paperwork to you all earlier
that showed the need. And my my quick
short answer that's as good as I can
give you is I don't control the postage
rates that the United States Post Office
decides to increase multiple times a
year. I also don't control the number of
civil cases that get filed in my court.
We are in a year 2025 where we are
seeing record numbers in our civil
division. Unfortunately, the Ohio
Revised Code tells me that I must serve
paperwork by certified mail. What
happens is I s spend the money, send it
out, certified mail. It gets it's
unclaimed. Then I have to s send it out
again by regular mail. So, our numbers
just keep going up and up and up. My
budget had been at 40,000 for years and
years and years. That was before me and
I left it at 40. I upped it to 50 a
couple of years ago. We have after the
the small chart that I sent to you
showed through the end of August and now
I'm showing through the end of
September. September we spent $8,552
from the clerk's office. It was actually
a total of $8,900 just over because that
included what the court spent as well.
And then we get a reimbursement from um
the court for their costs. Um, but we
are right now at $65,000
with the budget that was at $50,000 for
the year. And there is no way I could
have foreseen that coming. Um, I have
adjusted my budget for 2026. But my fear
right now is that if I have another
couple of months at nearly $9,000 or
even at $8,000, I'm going to go in the
red in my postage budget if I wait until
the 20th even of this month because I
don't know daytoday what I'm going to
spend. I have um numbers here if any of
you would like to see them of each day
of the month of September what was sent
out from my office. If anyone wants
that, I've got a copy of that. And then
I have the updated table that shows what
we spent that includes the month of
September as well. And I just I don't
want to get a call from the auditor's
office saying you have a problem in your
in your line item with postage. And and
I think that that's coming very very
soon if I if I don't get money moved
over there. So I'm just respectfully
asking if we could cut that to two
readings as opposed to three.
>> Miss Tina,
>> I do just have a question like with the
post office because I know it's
ridiculous what they charge to send
anything, but is there any You might
have said and I missed it. Is there a
bulk rate?
>> Oops. Is there a bulk rate or something
that we can get something through on the
post office? I know some places
try. Can you do anything like that? You
can't
>> I I don't I don't think that we can. We
don't get we I mean this is decades and
dec I've been there. But I just because
I do know
>> I can answer only because we use bulk
post. It has to be a certain amount at
the same time, right?
>> Like for the same mail.
>> Well, as much as you say you're sending
all the time,
>> they're doing it different
at different times.
>> And then they said they're sending
certified mail, which
>> right on top. I understand that, but I'm
just asking a question.
>> I've even looked into just because um
some clerk's offices have gone to FedEx
as opposed to the certified mail. the um
the general assembly had um made a
change and they will allow for FedEx
service. It's more it's more costly than
certified mail is. The benefit is and I
don't know that it's really going to
save any money because the benefit is
you spend more to send it out. The
effectiveness is you get better service
that you get a a better return on
service than you do if you're just
sending it certified mail by the post
office, but it's costing more initially.
So it's saving me that second mailing
that's change
sense that I I don't know that we're
going to gain any ground by spending
more initially on a FedEx service.
>> Any other questions?
>> One.
>> How much of this increase is due to the
legislation that was passed earlier this
year?
>> Some of it is some of it is also from
House Bill 29, the the change that came
in April. It is, but the bulk of it is
it's just basically our civil division
and sending things out by certified
mail. The increase from House Bill 29
that we've seen is that we now if if the
service has to go um of that new
supplemental citation, if they're not
local, we have to then send that out to
an adjacent county or a non-adjacent
county. We have to send that out to that
sheriff's department and or police
department. ask them to perfect the
service of the new citation. So, there
is cost involved with that. Good news is
I can tell you I've spoken with the
mayor and I spoken with uh law director
Hall, the one full-time employee that I
was granted back in se uh back in April,
May. Um I had said if I needed to come
back to you, I won't need to come back
to you. She is incredibly efficient.
She's doing a phenomenal job handling
all of that. That's pretty much all
she's handling in the office, but that's
that's what we hired her for. So,
>> any other questions?
Thank you. I don't see I it's my piece
through finance, so we'll ask for a
suspension when we get into second
readings.
>> Right. Thank you.
>> Y
All right. Any other
items for finance?
Seeing none, I will ask for a motion to
adjurnn.
>> So moved.
motion and a second. We are adjourned at
6:30 on the dot.
>> Lancaster City Council regular meeting
will con uh convene at 6:35.
The Frankie Smith Funeral Home and
Crematory in Lancaster and the Johnson
Smith Funeral Home in Baltimore have a
long and wonderful history of serving
our community. Feel free to give us a
call at 740-653652.
Stop in and see us at either of our two
locations, 405 North Columbus Street in
Lancaster and 207 South Main Street in
Baltimore. Respect for tradition, regard
for change.
Hi, this is the Senk family with the
Salvation Army of Fairfield County. Our
mission is to meet human needs without
discrimination. We provide a multitude
of services that focus on senior care
and preparing our youth for successful
futures. This month, we are excited to
be chosen by the Buckeye Automotive
Families Buckeye Cares program. They'll
make a donation with each car sold this
month. Thank you, Buckeye family, for
supporting the Salvation Army of
Fairfield County.
[Music]
Please rise if you're able and join in a
moment of prayer. God, grant us the
serenity to accept the things we cannot
change, the courage to change the things
we can, and finally, the wisdom to know
the difference.
I now call the Lancaster City Council
meeting uh to order for October 6.
Please join me in the pledge of
allegiance.
>> I pledge algiance to the flag of the
United States of America and to the
republic for which it stands, one nation
under God, indivisible, with liberty and
justice for all.
>> Please call the role.
>> Mr. Als,
>> Mr. Bisjack,
>> here.
>> Mrs. Kes,
>> I'm sorry, Mrs. Hoop
>> here.
>> Mr. Lockenberg
>> Mr. Skunover
>> here.
>> Mr. Sullie
>> Miss Tiner
>> here. And Mr. Wing
>> here.
>> Let the record reflect that there are
eight members of Lancaster City Council
present tonight. At this time, I'd
entertain a motion to excuse Council
Member Kes.
>> Mr. President, I'd like to make that
motion.
>> Second.
>> We have a motion and second to excuse
Council Member Kit. All those in favor,
please signify by saying I.
>> I. I.
>> Motion carries. I'd also like to take
this opportunity to make the
announcement that our recently appointed
council member um council member Bitler
um had to there was a conflict with her
position uh on the county port authority
board that was ascertained and she has
chosen to resign and retain that
position with the county port authority
board. Uh once again, she's in the
audience this evening, but I I want to
reiterate that we thank you for your
public service um and your past service
as council president. Thank you very
much.
>> Um we uh will now move on to the reading
and disposing of the journal.
>> Um regular meeting minutes dated
September 22nd, 2025.
>> Mr. President, I'd like to make a motion
to receive and file the journal.
>> Second. We have a motion, a second to
proceed and file the journal. All those
in favor, please signify by saying I. I.
>> I.
>> All those opposed, same sign.
>> We'll now move on to the reports of city
officials.
>> Email dated September 23rd, 2025
regarding um permanent resolution 47-25
Sheridan Drive Economic District.
Submitted by law director Stephanie
Hall. Email dated October 1st, 2025
regarding presentation requested SBA
disaster loan outreach center submitted
by President Porter. Series of emails
dated September 26 through October 2nd
um 2025. Intersections of of High Street
and Chestnut, High Street and 6th
Avenue, submitted by Lieutenant Chuck
Sims and Council Member Tener. Email
dated September 26, 2025 regarding the
August 25th U revenue report submitted
by income tax commissioner Amy Hamilton.
And that's the final one.
>> Mr. President, I'd like to make a motion
to receive and file the reports of city
officials.
>> Second.
>> We have a motion and a second to receive
and file the reports of city officials.
All those in favor, please signify by
saying I.
>> I. All those opposed, same sign.
>> Move on to communications.
>> I have four. I have email date September
22nd, 2025 regarding copies for past
legislation.
um submitted by uh Zach Gerald with
Columbus Business First. Email dated
September 25th, 2025 regarding trivia
to redevelop historic church into
mixeduse space in Lancaster submitted by
Stephanie Bosow with the Port of
Lancaster Port Authority.
Um, email dated September 26, 20 25
regarding um concerned citizen with
residents living near Google. Submitted
by Kelsey Wheeler. Uh, email dated
October 3rd, 2025 regarding curbside
recycling in Lancaster. Um, submitted by
Jake Hef Hefron with Rumpky Waste and
Recycling.
>> Mr. President, I'd like to make a motion
to receive and file the communications.
>> Second. a motion, a second to receive
and file the communications. All those
in favor, please signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> All those opposed, same sign.
>> We will now move on to special
presentations. And this evening, we have
Debbie Joyce Jaca with the US Small
Business Administration. If you'd like
to come forward, please.
>> Good evening, council mayor, council
president. My name is Can you hear me?
Okay. Okay. My name is DJ Ja. I'm a
public affairs specialist specifically
with the Small Business Administration's
Office of Disaster Recovery and
Resiliency, the Eastern Branch. And I am
here because, as you're well aware,
there was the flooding that occurred the
three days at the end of July. And as a
result of that, the Small Business
Administration is providing an agency
declaration that can allow survivors,
and survivors are a fairly lengthy list
these days, especially with an agency
declaration.
It's not just businesses, as our
namesake logo um says, but as well as
businesses, it's churches, it's um
homeowners, it's renters, it's um
agricultural cooperatives. So there is a
full and excuse me, private nonprofits.
So there's a full slate of organizations
and individuals that are able to access
lowinterest disaster loans. Um because
of the nature of it being an agency
declaration, just for your own
knowledge, obviously we are here in
Fairfield County. However, the
contiguous counties of Franklin,
Hawking, Licking, Perry, and Pickaway
are eligible for the exact same loans.
Typically, they're only eligible for the
economic injury, but they also are
available for the physical disaster. So,
when it comes to the physical disaster
loans, again, when I mentioned
nonprofits, churches, um, businesses,
those loan rates right now, and the
deadline isn't until November 12th, so
we're still um, within the range if
there's any that have not applied, that
they are eligible for up to um it would
be no more than um 4% if they have no
credit available elsewhere or 8% if
credit elsewhere. Um the physical
disaster loans for homeowners. Oh, and I
should note the business loans are up to
$2 million. Obviously, there's no
obligation to accept the full amount
that's offered. And um with home loans,
it's up to $500,000.
And the um key on all of our loans that
I want to emphasize now before I even
proceed is um the Small Business
Administration wants to see communities
succeed. and they know their businesses,
their nonprofits, their their um
neighborhoods are a key component of the
overall um community that there are no
payments and no interest for the first
12 months after you're approved and sign
and receive your loan and there's no um
accured um interest that builds during
that time. In fact, if you're in um
insurance were to come through, you can
use that to pay the loan and there's no
penalty. So they do everything, we do
everything in our power to ensure that
we're providing funding that allows
people to fully recover. Um, so I walked
roughly through the um, disaster loan,
the flyers I distributed. Um, the
piece I want to jump to is idol. The
deadline for that is longer for a
reason. And I kind of I have to admit I
do have, if you got to know me, you'd
find out quick I have a sarcastic
personality. An idol loan is anything
but idol. It's economic injury disaster
loan. It's actually meant to keep the
lights on and the doors open of
businesses. So there could be in the
coming months since the deadline extends
into the spring of 2026 businesses that
find out geez things kind of tailed off
after the um the flooding and you know I
don't I might have to um cut someone
from full-time to part-time or I wasn't
able to keep my inventory up. So, it's
uh um the idol, the economic injury is
working capital, which we find really
helps businesses um that didn't possibly
suffer any physical damages as a result
of the flooding, but they've seen a loss
of business as a result of it. It allows
them to keep um their doors open while
the community recovers. So, that is one
of um the featur um features of that
loan. The one that I emphas I want to
emphasize that um a lot of people um
aren't aware and there we're really
building our communication around at
this point is if a homeowner or business
did have physical damage and they've
qualified for a loan, they can get in
the next two years apply for up to 20%
of that loan. So the nice easy figure I
use, they qualified for $1,000 um to
repair the physical damage. they could
get another $200. Um, and again, it's a
two-year window in which to apply for it
to do mitigation work. There is a lot
more effort, and you probably hear about
it in the news, that areas that suffer
maybe repeated flooding or severe
weather circumstances, you want to do
things to make yourself resilient for
the next time around. So, we're offering
those additional funds that allow people
to do things to make sure what they're
trying to restore is in fact going to
survive through the next potential
potential bout of um damages. And that's
really all I wanted to share today. Um I
want to thank um um Lancaster for how
positive and inviting everyone has been.
We had a oper um outreach center that
closed last week that was open for
several weeks at the Fairfield Emergency
Management Office and um there's just
been an incredible amount of it's
Lancaster is a very nice place to be.
So, we're I'm hopeful we can do more to
um help you guys as needed recover from
what happened. And if you have any
questions, I'm here.
>> Do we have any questions from council
members?
hearing none. We thank you for coming
and presenting this evening.
>> All right. Thank you so much.
>> Thank you.
>> Petitions and memorials.
>> There are no petitions or memorials this
evening.
>> Thank you. We have now uh reached the
time for permission of voters and
taxpayers to address council. Are there
any individuals here this evening that
wish to address city council?
If you do, please come to the podium,
sign your name, and um your comments are
limited to three minutes.
My name is John Bradford. I'm from 1360
Frederick Street, Lancaster, Ohio. I'm
come here to speak in favor of the
proposed legislation to restrict
fireworks in our community. Ohio's new
firework law was signed on November of
2021 and took effect on July 1st, 2022.
This bill legalized the use of 1.4G 4G
consumer fireworks, which actually means
firecrackers, Roman candles, and
fountains on eight specific holidays.
This includes also in this law that was
passed by the state that you have to be
150 ft from any structure using an
aerial device, which basically means
there's no place in the city of
Lancaster that fits within that
category.
The the law also allows communities, the
state laws, to enact stricter laws.
Since that time when this law was
promoted by the state, um it's gotten
out of hand. Frankly, laws being broken
and people's peace and quality of life
has been diminished.
The past Labor Day weekend, no less than
three Lancaster neighborhoods
experienced extreme and illegal firework
displays by people either ignorant of
the law or they just chose to disregard
it. In each of these cases, debris from
the aerial fireworks fell on house roofs
and in yards. There was it was still
hot.
The silent majority of the electorate do
not want their peace and quality of life
disrupted by this type of behavior. The
new legislation will make enforcement of
firework laws easier to interpret and to
enforce by the police department and the
fire department.
Thank you for passing this upcoming
legislation.
>> Thank you, sir. Are there any other
individuals who wish to address council
at this time? Please come forward.
I'm Kathy Bitler, 774 Lamp Circle East
in Lancaster. President Porter and
members of council, it's it's been my
very great pleasure to serve the city of
Lancaster as an atlarge member of this
body since late last July.
Unfortunately, that service has come to
an end and my resignation was submitted
to President Porter on Friday with
copies sent to Mayor McDaniel, Law
Director Hall, the Board of Elections,
and the Republican uh Party Central
Committee. My resignation was effective
immediately.
Less than an hour before I submitted the
resignation, I was made aware of an
attorney general's opinion that I could
not serve council and the Fairfield
County Port Authority Board at the same
time. I made no secret of my involvement
with the port authority during this
selection process. But had I been aware
of that attorney general's decision, I
would not have allowed my name to go to
the central committee. I apologize to
this body for that error on my part.
It's unlikely to back out of a
commitment and that's why I chose to
resign from council rather than the port
authority. I had committed to the port
authority position in 2024 and therefore
as it my first commitment I was honor
bound to stay there.
Of late some have expressed concern that
I was appointed to fill the unexpired
seat here specifically because of a
single issue. I just want to say
publicly that I find that idea offensive
to me, to the members of council, and to
the central committee members who voted
for me. My love of and desire to help
this city were my only interests and
remain so today. I want to thank each
and every member of this body for
welcoming me, answering my questions
over the last few months, and making me
feel welcome again.
It's clear that each of you has the best
interest of the residents of Lancaster
at heart. I encourage you to continue to
ask questions and to seek the best
possible solutions to all of our issues.
Thank you.
>> Thank you for your comments this
evening. Is there anybody else who
wishes to address city council at this
time?
Hearing none, we thank you for attending
tonight's meeting.
Now move on to the reports of standing
committees.
>> I have three um finance committee
meeting minutes dated September 23rd,
2025 and October 6, 2025 submitted by
Mr. Skunover. Finance committee meeting
agenda dated October 6, 2025 submitted
by Mr. Skunover.
>> I I lost count.
>> Sorry, I blended the two.
>> Uh you did. Thank you. Mr. President,
I'd like to make a motion to receive and
file receive and file the reports of
standing committees.
>> Second.
>> We have a motion and a second to receive
and file the reports of standing
committees. All those in favor, please
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> All those opposed, same sign.
>> Reports of special committees.
>> There are none.
>> No public hearing this evening. We will
now move on to the reading of
resolutions.
There are no third reading of
resolutions. So, we will move to second
readings beginning with temporary
resolution 7925. a resolution to
authorize the service safety director to
apply for a grant through the Ohio
Public Works Commission to fund the Ree
Avenue and Hubert or West Huber Avenue
rehabilitation project and to declare an
emergency. This is through public works
committee. Mrs. Tiner and Mr.
Luckenberg,
>> Council Member Tiner,
>> second of three readings.
>> Second of three readings on temporary
resolution 7925,
temporary resolution 8025.
Um, a resolution to authorize the
service safety director to advertise for
bids and enter into contracts for mowing
and trimming the city cemeteries. This
through public works committee, Miss
Tiner and Mrs. Kurtz.
>> Council member Tiner.
>> Second of three readings.
>> Second of three readings on temporary
resolution 8025. Temporary resolution
8125. A resolution to authorize the law
director to negotiate and enter into a
contract with the city of Reynoldsburg
and the prosecution of adult misdemeanor
traffic and criminal offenses
committed in the city of Reynoldsburg
Reynoldsburg within Fairfield County,
Ohio and to accept payment for the same.
This is through finance committee Mr.
Skunover and Mr. Als Council member
Skunover.
>> A second of three readings, please.
>> Second of three readings and temporary
resolution 8125.
Temporary resolution 8225,
>> a resolution to appropriate from the
unencumber balance and amend the
certificate of appropriations with the
county auditor and the general fund
10001. This through finance committee,
Mr. Skunover and Mr. AS.
>> Council member Skunover.
>> Mr. President, I'd like to make a motion
that council suspend its rules and wave
the third reading of temporary
resolution 8225.
>> Second. We have a motion, a second to
suspend the rules and wave the third
reading of temporary resolution 8225.
Discussion, council member Skunover.
>> Uh just briefly on the suspension, clerk
Sloan uh was in finance. Uh this is the
piece for additional funding for her
budget for postage,
which is crazy the amount that we have
to spend on that, but it is what it is.
So we're going to be asking for
suspension so that account doesn't go in
the red for her.
>> Thank you. Any further discussion?
Hearing none, please call the role.
>> Mr. Als, yes.
>> Mr. Bishek, yes.
>> Mrs. Kry, I'm sorry.
>> Mrs. Hoop,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Luxembourg?
>> Yes.
>> Mr. Skunover?
>> Mr. Sullie?
>> Yes.
>> Miss Tiner?
>> And Mr. Ming?
>> Yes.
>> Motion to suspend passes 8 to zero.
Council members.
>> Mr. President, I'd like to make a motion
that council pass and gross and enter
upon the written record temporary
resolution 8225.
>> Second. A motion and a second to pass
and gross and enter upon the written
record temporary resolution 8225. Any
further discussion? Not for me. Any
further discussion? Hearing none, please
call the role.
>> Mr. Als,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Bisjack,
>> Mrs. Hoop,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Luckenberg,
>> Mr. Skuniver,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Sully,
>> Miss Tiner,
>> yes.
>> And Mr. Wing,
>> Motion to pass and gross and enter upon
the written record temporary resolution
8225 passes 8 to zero.
We'll now move on to the first reading
of resolutions beginning with temporary
resolution 8325.
>> A resolution to make appropriations for
planned 2000 or 2026
budget expenses and other expenditures
of the city of Lancaster for fiscal year
2026 and to establish line item transfer
authority for all city departments. Mr.
Finance committee, Mr. Sully and I'm
sorry, Mr. Skunover and Mr. Sully.
Council member Skunover,
>> this is a first of three readings,
please.
>> First of three readings on temporary
resolution 8325. Temporary resolution
8425,
>> a resolution to increase and decrease
appropriations in the general fund
for the Lancaster Fire Department
overtime and to declare an emergency.
This is through safety committee, Mr.
Bisjack and Miss Tener.
>> Council member Bisjack.
>> Thank you, Mr. President. This is the
first three readings. First of three
readings on temporary resolution 8425.
Temporary resolution 8525.
>> A resolution to appropriate from the
unencumbered balance in the health
insurance management fund 7022
to amend the certificate of
appropriations with the Fairfro County
Auditor and to declare an emergency.
This is through administrative services
committee. Mr. Lockchenberg and Mr.
Bisjek.
>> Council member Lockenberg.
>> Thank you, Mr. President. First of three
readings. First of three readings on
temporary resolution 8525.
Temporary resolution 8625.
>> A resolution accepting the amounts in
rates as determined by the Fairfolk
County Budget Commission authorizing the
necessary tax levies and certifying them
to the county auditor and to declare an
emergency. This through finance
committee, Mr. Skunover, Mr. Als.
>> Council member Skunover.
>> Mr. President, I'd like to make a motion
that council suspend its rules and wave
the second and third readings of
temporary resolution 8625.
>> Second motion, a second to suspend the
rules and wave the second and third
reading of temporary resolution 8625.
Discussion, council members,
>> we're asking for suspension on this
piece because we're past due on getting
this back to the county auditor. Thank
you. Any further discussion?
Hearing none, please call the role on
the motion to suspend.
>> Mr. Als,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Bisjack,
>> Mrs. Hoop,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Lenberg,
>> Mr. Skunberg,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Sully,
>> Miss Tiner,
>> yes.
>> And Mr. Wing,
>> Motion to suspend the rules. We have the
second and third reading of temporary
resolution 8625 passes 8 to zero.
>> Council member Skunover.
>> Mr. President, I'd like to make a motion
that council pass and gross and enter
upon the written record temporary
resolution 8625.
Second
>> a motion and a second to pass and gross
and enter upon the written record
temporary resolution 8625.
Any further discussion?
>> No sir.
>> Hearing none, please call a role.
>> Mr. Als, yes.
>> Mr. Bisjack,
>> yes.
>> Mrs. Hoop,
>> Mr. Lenberg,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Skunover,
>> Mr. Sullie,
>> yes.
>> Miss Ter,
>> And Mr. Wing,
>> yes.
>> Motion to pass and gross and enter upon
the written record temporary resolution
8625 passes 8 to zero. We will now move
on to the reading of ordinances
beginning with the third uh reading of
temporary ordinance 4625.
>> An ordinance to accept the annexation of
163.434
plus or minus acres in the Greenfield
Township and to declare an emergency.
Mr. Economic Development, Mrs. Hoop and
Mrs. K. So
Mr. Skoonover.
>> Okay.
>> All right. Council member Hoop.
>> Um, yes, Mr. President. I'd like to make
a motion that council pass engross and
enter upon the written record temporary
ordinance 46-25.
>> Second. We have a motion second to pass
gross and enter upon the written record
temporary uh ordinance 4625. Any
discussion?
>> Um, this is just to accept the
annexation of the 163 acres
in the Rockill Industrial Park.
>> Thank you. Any further discussion?
Hearing none, please call the role.
>> Mr. Als, yes.
>> Mr. Bischack,
>> yes.
>> Mrs. Hoop,
>> Mr. Lockenberg,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Skunover,
>> Mr. Sully,
>> yes.
>> Miss Tiner,
>> And Mr. Wing,
>> yes.
>> Motion to pass. Gross and upon the
written record, temporary ordinance 4625
passes 8 to zero.
>> Temporary ordinance 4725.
>> An ordinance to amend the zoning map
subject to passage of the annexation of
163.434 434 plus or minus acres in
Greenville Township and de to declare an
emergency. Economic development
committee, Mrs. Hoop and Mr. Wing.
>> Council member Hoop.
>> Yes, Mr. President. I'd like to make a
motion to replace temporary ordinance
47-25
with
temporary ordinance 47-25
star as given to the clerk in writing
prior to tonight's meeting.
>> Second. We have a motion in the second
to um replace temporary ordinance 4725
with temporary ordinance 47-25
star as provided to the clerk in writing
prior to tonight's meeting. Any
discussion? Council member who?
>> Not right now.
>> Thank you. Any further discussion
hearing? None. Please call the role.
>> Mr. Als, yes.
>> Mr. Bisjack,
>> yes.
>> Mrs. Hoop,
>> Mr. Luenberg,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Skunver,
>> Mr. Sullie,
>> yes.
>> Miss Ter,
>> yes. and Mr. Wing.
>> Yes.
>> Motion to replace uh temporary ordinance
4725 with temporary ordinance 47-25
star passes 8 to zero. Council member
who?
>> Yes, Mr. President. I'd like to make a
motion that council pass and gross and
enter upon the written record temporary
ordinance 47-25
star.
>> Second.
>> Have a motion to second to pass and
gross and enter upon the written record
temporary ordinance 47-25
star. Any discussion? Um this is just
the for the same annexation we just
voted on but to set the zoning to
advance manufacturing.
>> Thank you. Any further discussion?
>> Hearing none, please call the role.
>> Mr. Als,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Bishack,
>> Mrs. Hoop,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Lockchenberg,
>> Mr. Skunover,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Sully,
>> Miss Tinder,
>> yes.
>> And Mr. Wing,
>> Motion to pass and gross and enter upon
the written record temporary ordinance
47-25 star passes 8 to zero. We now move
on to second reading beginning with
temporary ordinance 49-25
>> an ordinance to establish benefits
titles and compensation for parks and
declar and recreation personnel employed
by the city of Lancaster Ohio for the
year 2026 and to declare an emergency
this through administrative services
committee Mr. Luxenberg and Mr. Bisj,
>> Council Member Luenberg.
>> Second of three readings, please.
>> Second of three readings on temporary
ordinance 4925.
Temporary ordinance 5125,
>> an ordinance providing for the issuance
and sale of the notes in the maximum
principal amount of $180,000
in anticipation of the issuance of bonds
for the purpose of paying the cost of
the renovation of an existing building
for the for use by the city's municipal
court. together with all necessary
impertinences thereto in declaring an
emergency this through finance committee
Mr. Skunover and Mr. Sully.
>> Council member Skunover. So first of
three readings please.
>> You mean second of three readings?
>> I'm sorry. Yes. Second.
>> Yeah. Second.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Second of three readings on temporary
ordinance 5125.
Temporary ordinance 5225. an ordinance
to authorize the mayor to accept a
perpetual easement for roadway purposes
on East Fair Avenue and to declare an
emergency. This is through public works
committee, Miss Tiner and Mr.
Lockenberg.
>> Council member Tiner.
>> Uh, Mr. President, I'd like to make a
motion that we
You know what? I forgot to get my hand
open.
Mr. President, I would like to make a
motion that council suspend its rules
and wave the third reading of temporary
ordinance 5225.
>> Second.
>> We have a motion a second to suspend the
rules and wave the third reading of
temporary ordinance 5225.
Any discussion on the motion to suspend
council?
>> Not at this time.
>> Thank you. Any further hearing? None.
Please call a role.
>> Mr. Als,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Bischack,
>> Mrs. Hoop,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Luenberg,
>> Mr. Skover.
>> Yes.
>> Mr. Sullie,
>> yes.
>> Miss Tiner,
>> And Mr. Wing,
>> yes.
>> Motion to suspend the rules and wait the
third reading of temporary ordinance
5225.
Passes 8 to zero. Council member Tener.
>> Mr. President, I'd like to make a motion
that council passing and gross and enter
upon the written record temporary
ordinance 5225.
>> Second.
>> We have a motion and a second to pass
and gross and enter upon the written
record temporary ordinance 5225.
Any discussion?
>> Yes. This is so that we can accept an
easement for Ohio Bell. Not Ohio Bell.
Oh my gosh. Ohio Bell. I'm going to the
BBF after we're done here.
>> All right.
>> Oh no. Ohio Power Company. So sorry.
So that they can expand their substation
on Fair Avenue.
>> Thank you. Any further discussion?
>> Hearing none, please call the RO.
>> Mr. Als, yes. Mr. Bisj, yes. Mrs. Hoop,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Lockenberg.
>> Yes.
>> Mr. Skunover.
>> Goodness. Mr. Sully,
>> yes.
>> Miss Tiner,
>> And Mr. Wing,
>> yes.
>> Motion to pass and gross and enter upon
the written record temporary ordinance
5225 passes 8 to zero. Temporary
ordinance 5325.
>> An ordinance to amend um Lancaster
codified ordinance part five general
offenses code and adopt chapter 550
fireworks. This through law committee.
>> I'll take that, Mr. President. Yes,
>> Mr. Bisjack.
>> Council member Bisjack.
>> Thank you, Mr. President. That'll be the
second of three readings.
>> Second of three readings on temporary
ordinance 5325.
Now move on to first reading of
ordinances beginning with 5425.
an ordinance to authorize the service
safety director to enter into an FFC
notification
for spectrum manager lease and spectrum
lease agreement with census for the
implementation of the smart metering
initiative by Lancaster Mun Municipal
Gas. This is through service committee
Mr. Als and Mr. Wing.
>> Council member Als readings please.
>> First of three readings on temporary
ordinance 5425.
Temporary ordinance 5525,
>> an ordinance to establish the
compensation for the council president,
council members, and the council clerk
for the term commencing payroll one of
2026. This through finance committee,
Mr. Skunover, and Mr. Sully.
>> Council member Skunover. First of three
readings, please.
>> First of three readings on temporary
ordinance 5525.
Temporary Ordinance 5625,
>> an emergency ordinance declaring the
improvement to certain parcels
associated with the Sheridan Drive
project in the city to be a public
purpose and exempt from taxation
pursuant to OC 5709.40B
requiring the owners of those parcels to
make service payments in lie of taxes.
the owners of those parcels. I'm sorry,
authorizing the city to require minimum
service payments and such payments are
agreed upon by developer establishing a
municipal building and
>> municipal public improvement
>> municipal public improvement tax
increment equivalent fund for the
deposit of those services payments and
as applicable minimum service payments
authorizing payments to the Lancaster
City School District specific or
specifying the public infrastructure
improvements that directly benefit the
parcels and approving related matters.
Mr. Economic Development Committee, Mrs.
Hoop and Mrs. Crates,
>> Council Member Hoop,
>> first of three readings.
>> First of three readings on temporary
ordinance 5625.
That um brings us to the end of our
regular um list of reading of
our resolutions and ordinances. There
remain two um pieces of legislation that
are currently tabled. I don't believe
those will be removed. Um we'll move to
any unfinished business by council
members.
Hearing none new business. Um, I guess.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. I would like to address uh Kathy
Bitler. Um, she's a very honest person.
I'm so glad I I She started I when I
started being on council, she was our
president at the time. So, I kind of
started with her and I've ended with
her. And uh she's a very honest person.
Uh I actually was one of the ones that
suggested her because that's who I
thought to fill the position. And uh I
don't know of her being anything but
honest. So, and I'm so glad that she did
serve and I I thank you very much.
>> Thank you, Council Member Tiner. Uh,
we'll move to new business beginning
with we're going to go around and do our
committee reports if that's okay or do
you want to add something council member
>> just real quick because I know the on
the communications to council can
like I I remember there was one that I
know that was sent out to all of us. Um,
but there were a couple that the clerk
read that I didn't see. So, can you
forward those to everybody?
>> I sure can.
>> It's like the trivia one on the
redevelopment of the church. I saw it on
Facebook, but I I didn't realize we got
a notice of it.
>> Yeah, that one was submitted um through
um
Stephanie Bosco. So, I will forward that
one to you.
>> Okay.
>> And to all.
>> Thank you.
>> You're welcome. Thank you.
>> All right, we'll move to committee
updates. We'll switch sides. We'll begin
with Council Member Sulli.
>> Nothing new to report at this time.
>> Thank you, Council Member Bisjack.
>> Uh safety committee's meeting this
Friday, 8:00 in the morning, 1897 room.
We'll be discussing the budgets of the
fire department and police department.
That's all, Mr. President. Thank you.
>> Thank you, Council Member Luckenberg.
>> Administrative Services meeting a week
from next Wednesday, same time, same
place.
>> Thank you very much, Council Member Als.
>> Nothing new to report. Thank you very
much. Council member Tener.
>> Nothing.
>> Okay. Council member Skooner.
>> Um, just your friendly budget reminder.
Everybody has it now. And I think the
committee meetings kind of worked out.
So, everybody should be able to hash out
stuff during their committee meeting and
any new findings, I would encourage you
to send an email to everyone. So, you're
the expert of your committee and those
departments. So, love to see emails from
everybody on on their budget process.
Thank you,
>> Council Member Wing.
>> Yes. Uh, thank you, Mr. President. Uh,
the next meeting for the Water and Water
Pollution Control Committee is actually
is two weeks from today on October 20th
at 7:30 in the morning. Um, and I think
everyone has probably seen this by now,
but I just want to highlight that last
Wednesday was a very special day for the
water department. uh after years of hard
work and late nights, uh the ribbon
cutting and and dedication happened uh
last Wednesday afternoon and I just
wanted to add it was a very special day.
Um great to see so many city departments
represented and all the stakeholders
coming together to to celebrate a job
well done.
>> Thank you and great work. Uh, Council
Member Hoop.
>> Um, nothing new other than the much
anticipated committee meeting on October
30th at 7:30 in the morning.
>> Okay. Thank you,
>> Mr. President. I said same time, same
place. Mine's going to be at 8:00. I
work for not 7:30.
>> All right. Thank you. Thank you for that
clarification, Council Member Luck.
>> Um, we we appreciate it. So, we're going
to announce uh announcement of scheduled
meetings. I have next regular sessions
of council is October 20th, 2025 at 6:30
p.m. here in council chambers and then
again November 3rd at 2025 at 6:30 here
in council chambers.
>> Thank you. Special scheduled meetings.
>> I have none this evening.
>> Regular scheduled committee meetings.
>> I have finance committee October
10. I'm sorry, scratch that. That's
today.
>> October 10th. Um, safety committee
meeting October 10th at 8 a.m. Uh, city
hall 1897 conference room.
Administrative committee meeting um
October 15th at 8 a.m. City Hall 1897
conference room. Water water pollution
committee meeting October 20th at 7:38
a.m. Um, city hall 1897 conference room
and economic development committee
meeting October 30th at 7:30 a.m. City
Hall 1897 conference room. Thank you.
Reading of bills.
>> I have two this evening. Um, one for
MNCO, $228.112
for publications of ordinances. I have
another for MNCO of $7548
for public hearing notice.
>> Mr. President, I'd like to make a motion
we pay the bills.
>> Second.
>> Have a motion, a second to pay the
bills. All those in favor, please
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Okay. Paid the bills. No need for an
executive session this evening. I will
entertain a motion to adjurnn.
>> Mr. President, I'd like to make that
motion. We adjourn.
>> Second.
>> We have a motion and second to adjurnn.
All those in favor, please signify by
saying I.
>> I.
>> All those opposed, same sign. We are
adjourned. Please remember to sign your
legislation.
Thanks.
[Music]